Browning W. Ware papers, Inclusive: 1928-2002, undated, Bulk: 1954-1988
Baylor University, The Texas Collection
Browning W. Ware papers
Inclusive: 1928-2002, undated, Bulk: 1954-1988
Baylor University, The Texas Collection http://www.baylor.edu/lib/texas/
3885
Ware, Browning W.
42 document boxes.
The Browning W. Ware papers contain the materials of noted Texas pastor Browning W. Ware, who was best known for leading First Baptist Church, Austin Texas, and many other religious and civic organizations.
Administrative Information
Physical Description
General condition: Average.
Biography/Profile
Browning Worth Ware, longtime pastor, author, and church leader, was an important contemporary of Baptist figures Foy Valentine, Charles Wellborn, and other Southern Baptist leaders. Ware pastored Texas churches in Beaumont, Denton, Cleburne, Hubbard, Satin, and Austin, and wrote a column called "Diary of a Modern Pilgrim" that ran in the Austin-American Statesman and other newspapers for over 40 years.
Ware was born in Fort Worth, Texas, on 1928 November 5 to J.W. and Myrtle Haralson Ware. The oldest of five children, Browning Ware attended Woodrow Wilson High School in Dallas, Texas, then went to Baylor University. He graduated from Baylor with a B.A. and Southwestern Baptist Theological Seminary with a B.D. and Th.D.
Browning Ware married twice, first to Corinne S. Ware in 1950. They had three children together: Brooks Browning Ware, Suzanne Ware Luper, and Camille Ware Kress. Browning and Corinne Ware divorced in 1985. Ware married Juanell Wright Ware in 1987.
He was best-known for his 20 years of service at the then-1,700 member First Baptist Church in Austin, Texas. Along with leading pastoral ministries, he also served in the community, including with the Austin Ethics Commission, Cystic Fibrosis Foundation, and various mental health organizations. His weekly column "Diary of a Modern Pilgrim" was run in multiple newspapers throughout the state, but was especially well-known in the Austin-American Statesman. On the state and national levels, he was an active leader in what later became the Baptist General Convention of Texas, the Southern Baptist Convention, and was Chaplain of the Texas House and Senate for fourteen years.
After many years of dedicated service to God and the people of his church and community, Browning Ware passed away from cancer on 2002 November 1. He is buried in the Texas State Cemetery in Austin, Texas.
Scope and Content
The Browning W. Ware papers documents the efforts of Browning W. Ware as he led Baptist churches throughout Texas. It also contains materials on civic organizations Ware was involved in, as well as personal and university-related papers. Topics represented in the collection include Baptist life as a pastor in Texas, Ware's studies at Southwestern Baptist Theological Seminary, his work in various civic organizations in Austin, Texas, general Baptist materials, and other topics. Material types include correspondence, literary productions, printed materials, financial documents, and others. Formats represented in the collection include photographs, 2 color slides, and a large number of phonodiscs.
Arrangement
The Browning W. Ware papers were organized by subject, type, and function prior to this finding aid. Most materials were in folders with titles, but some folders did not have titles. Original order was maintained as much as possible. The level of processing deemed appropriate for this collection differs from other record groups at The Texas Collection.
Currently, the Browning W. Ware papers are arranged in six series: I. Pastoral Life, II. "Diary of a Modern Pilgrim" Articles, III. Personal Materials, IV. University Studies, V. Sermons, VI. Audio Records.
Access Restrictions
All requests for copying of materials must be submitted to The Texas Collection in writing. Please use the Request Form for Copying Materials sheet. Unpublished materials authored or otherwise produced by the creator (s) of this collection are in the public domain. There are no restrictions on use. Copyright status for other collection materials is unknown. Transmission or reproduction of materials protected by U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) beyond that allowed by fair use requires the written permission of the copyright owners. Works not in the public domain cannot be commercially exploited without permission of the copyright owners. Responsibility for any use rests exclusively with the user.
Acquisition Information
Accession No. 3885. Acquired 2013-04-12
Related Resources
Related references
Dilday, Russ. "Even in Dying, Browning Ware Listened and Learned." Baptist Standard. 2002 November 11. Accessed 2014 August 18.
Haralson, Hal. "Remembering Browning Ware." Christian Ethics Today. 2010 December 27. Accessed 2014 August 18.
"Browning Worth Ware." Texas State Cemetery. Accessed 2014 August 18.
" Juanell Wright Ware." Texas State Cemetery. Accessed 2014 August 18.
First Baptist Church. Into His Marvelous Light: 150 Year History of First Baptist Church, Austin, Texas. Austin, Texas: Nortex Press, 2001.
"Browning Ware." The Baptist Standard. 2002 November 4. Accessed 2014 August 18.
Index Terms
Subjects (Organizations)
Baptist General Convention of Texas -- History.; First Baptist Church (Austin, Tex.) -- History.; Southern Baptist Convention -- History -- 20th century.; Southern Baptist Convention -- Texas -- Clergy -- Biography.; Southern Baptist Convention.; Southwestern Baptist Theological Seminary -- History.
Places
Texas -- History.; Texas -- Race relations.
Subjects
Baptist associations -- United States.; Baptists -- Sermons.; Education, Higher -- Texas -- History.
Genres
Clippings (Books, newspapers, etc.); Correspondence.; Interviews (Sound recordings)
- Pastoral Life, 1928-2000, undated; 1
  Administrative Information
  Physical Description
  General condition: Average.
  Biography/Profile
  This series contains materials from Browning Ware's long service as a Baptist pastor. Much of what he wrote was not able to be traced to a specific church that he pastored, especially since he preached so often at neighboring church services and revivals.
  - Letter to Browning Ware from his mother, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence (1 of 2), 1965 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence (2 of 2), 1965 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, Letters to the Author (1 of 2), 1964-1966 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, Letters to the Author (2 of 2), 1964-1966 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence (1 of 3), 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence (2 of 3), 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence (3 of 3), 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Bible Studies, General, 1961-1966 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Bible Studies, “Nehemiah”, circa 1965 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Bible Studies, “Caleb: Facing the Difficult”, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Bible Studies, “Transformed to Christ Personhood”, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Bible Studies, “Hallelujah Chorus”, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Bible Studies, “The Source of Our Faith”, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Bible Studies, “A New Heaven and a New Earth”, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Bible Studies, “Christ Speaks to His Churches”, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Bible Studies, “Assurance for the Faithful”, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Bible Studies, “Truly God, Truly Man”, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Bible Studies, “Walking in the Light”, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Bible Studies, “Witness in Suffering”, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Bible Studies, “Living Expectantly”, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Bible Studies, “Love One Another”, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Bible Studies, “What Faith Requires”, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Bible Studies, “God’s Own People”, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Bible Studies, “Christ Our Mediator”, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Bible Studies, “Extremism”, undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Bible Studies, “Jethro: Giving Good Advice”, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Bible Studies, “Samson”, undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Bible Studies, “Josiah: Delight in the Law”, undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Bible Studies, “The Life of Simon Peter”, undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Bible Studies, “Jonathan”, undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Bible Studies, “Jeremiah”, undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Bible Studies, “Isaiah”, undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Bible Studies, “Hannah: Self-Giving Mother”, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Bible Studies, “Amos”, undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Bible Studies, “Naaman”, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Bible Studies, “Joseph”, undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Bible Studies, “An Overview of John’s Gospel” (1 of 2), undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Bible Studies, “An Overview of John’s Gospel” (2 of 2), undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Bible Studies, “Church Staffs”, undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Bible Studies, “War and Peace”, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Bible Studies, General, undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Holy Week (1 of 3), 1981-1986 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Holy Week (2 of 3), 1981-1986 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Holy Week (3 of 3), 1981-1986 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Adult Bible Study (1 of 7), 1969-1972 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Adult Bible Study (2 of 7), 1969-1972 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Adult Bible Study (3 of 7), 1969-1972 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Adult Bible Study (4 of 7), 1969-1972 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Adult Bible Study (5 of 7), 1969-1972 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Adult Bible Study (6 of 7), 1969-1972 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Adult Bible Study (7 of 7), 1969-1972 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Open Windows Devotionals, 1962-1966 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Small Group Resources, circa 1972 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Calvary Baptist Church Revival, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Speaking Engagements and Notes (1 of 5), circa 1964 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Speaking Engagements and Notes (2 of 5), circa 1964 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Speaking Engagements and Notes (3 of 5), circa 1964 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Speaking Engagements and Notes (4 of 5), circa 1964 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Speaking Engagements and Notes (5 of 5), circa 1964 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Sermon and Speaking Notes (1 of 4), circa 1967-1970 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Sermon and Speaking Notes (2 of 4), circa 1967-1970 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Sermon and Speaking Notes (3 of 4), circa 1967-1970 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Sermon and Speaking Notes (4 of 4), circa 1967-1970 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - “Exodus from a Christian Perspective”, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - “Great River”, undated (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Religious Emphasis Weeks, 1956-1957 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Religious Tolerance, undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Ethics, General (1 of 2), circa 1952-1953 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Ethics, General (2 of 2), circa 1952-1953 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Ethics, Communism (1 of 2), 1952-1961 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Ethics, Communism (2 of 2), 1952-1961 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Ethics, Christian Life Commission Youth Pamphlets, undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Ethics, Public Education, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Ethics, Drugs (1 of 2), 1951-1952 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Ethics, Drugs (2 of 2), 1951-1952 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Ethics, Daily Work, undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Council on Alcoholism, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Separation of Church and State (1 of 2), 1949-1954 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Separation of Church and State (2 of 2), 1949-1954 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - “The Minister Looks in a Mirror” (1 of 2), 1964-1965 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - “The Minister Looks in a Mirror” (2 of 2), 1964-1965 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - “The Narrow Bridge” and “The Uniqueness of Old Testament Ethics”, undated (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - “Five Years Revisited”, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Church Administration Articles, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Church Administration, “Building Relationships”, circa 1974 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - General. Publications, 1974-1985 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Baptist Press, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Baptist Standard, Correspondence (1 of 3), 1974-1975 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Baptist Standard, Correspondence (2 of 3), 1974-1975 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Baptist Standard, Correspondence (3 of 3), 1974-1975 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Baptist Standard, Articles, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Lessons Written for Baptist Standard (1 of 3), 1974 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Lessons Written for Baptist Standard (2 of 3), 1974 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Lessons Written for Baptist Standard (3 of 3), 1974 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Minister’s Frustrations (1 of 2), undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Minister’s Frustrations (2 of 2), undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Alcoholism Information Week Kit, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Fort Worth Council on Alcoholism (1 of 2), 1958-1959 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Fort Worth Council on Alcoholism (2 of 2), 1958-1959 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Christian Education Commission Packet (1 of 2), 1961 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Christian Education Commission Packet (2 of 2), 1961 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Christian Education Commission (1 of 3), 1961 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Christian Education Commission (2 of 3), 1961 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Christian Education Commission (3 of 3), 1961 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Other Church Communion Practices, 1956-1957 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Notes, Religion and Freedom, circa 1948-1957 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Pastoral Ministry Class, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Conference Travel (1 of 2), 1968 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Conference Travel (2 of 2), 1968 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Race and Christianity, undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Baptist General Convention of Texas True Love Waits, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - “When the Minister is Angry with His Denomination”, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Funerals, undated (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - “Understanding Young People” article, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Holy Week (1 of 2), 1971 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Holy Week (2 of 2), 1971 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Youth Evangelism, 1951-1953 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Christian Education, undated (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Christian Education Commission (1 of 4), 1960-1961 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Christian Education Commission (2 of 4), 1960-1961 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Christian Education Commission (3 of 4), 1960-1961 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Christian Education Commission (4 of 4), 1960-1961 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Fundraising for First Baptist Church, Cleburne, 1960 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Professional Development, 1960 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - 90th Anniversary Heritage Day for First Baptist Church, Cleburne, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Church and State (1 of 2), 1952-1960 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Church and State (2 of 2), 1952-1960 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Appreciation Booklet, 1966-1967 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - 10th Anniversary at First Baptist Church, Austin (1 of 2), 1985 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - 10th Anniversary at First Baptist Church, Austin (2 of 2), 1985 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Christian Life Workshop, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Christian Life Workshop, 1961 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Sunday School Class Workshop, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Retirement (1 of 2), 1996 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Retirement (2 of 2), 1996 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - General, 1976-1996 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Notes (1 of 2), 1953-1980 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Notes (2 of 2), 1953-1980 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Notes, undated (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Notes and Notebooks (1 of 11), undated (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Notes and Notebooks (2 of 11), undated (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Notes and Notebooks (3 of 11), undated (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Notes and Notebooks (4 of 11), undated (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Notes and Notebooks (5 of 11), undated (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Notes and Notebooks (6 of 11), undated (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Notes and Notebooks (7 of 11), undated (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Notes and Notebooks (8 of 11), undated (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Notes and Notebooks (9 of 11), undated (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Notes and Notebooks (10 of 11), undated (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Notes and Notebooks (11 of 11), undated (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Notes (1 of 28), circa 1973 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Notes (2 of 28), circa 1973 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Notes (3 of 28), circa 1973 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Notes (4 of 28), circa 1973 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Notes (5 of 28), circa 1973 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Notes (6 of 28), circa 1973 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Notes (7 of 28), circa 1973 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Notes (8 of 28), circa 1973 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Notes (9 of 28), circa 1973 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Notes (10 of 28), circa 1973 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Notes (11 of 28), circa 1973 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Notes (12 of 28), circa 1973 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Notes (13 of 28), circa 1973 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Notes (14 of 28), circa 1973 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Notes (15 of 28), circa 1973 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Notes (16 of 28), circa 1973 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Notes (17 of 28), circa 1973 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Notes (18 of 28), circa 1973 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Notes (19 of 28), circa 1973 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Notes (20 of 28), circa 1973 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Notes (21 of 28), circa 1973 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Notes (22 of 28), circa 1973 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Notes (23 of 28), circa 1973 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Notes (24 of 28), circa 1973 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Notes (25 of 28), circa 1973 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Notes (26 of 28), circa 1973 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Notes (27 of 28), circa 1973 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Notes (28 of 28), circa 1973 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Clippings (1 of 10), 1953-1996 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Clippings (2 of 10), 1953-1996 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Clippings (3 of 10), 1953-1996 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Clippings (4 of 10), 1953-1996 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Clippings (5 of 10), 1953-1996 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Clippings (6 of 10), 1953-1996 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Clippings (7 of 10), 1953-1996 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Clippings (8 of 10), 1953-1996 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Clippings (9 of 10), 1953-1996 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Clippings (10 of 10), 1953-1996 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Clippings (1 of 5), 1962-2000 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Clippings (2 of 5), 1962-2000 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Clippings (3 of 5), 1962-2000 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Clippings (4 of 5), 1962-2000 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Clippings (5 of 5), 1962-2000 (Box 11, Folder 20)
- "Diary of a Modern Pilgrim" Articles, 1963-2002, undated; 2
  This series contains materials from Ware's regular newspaper column "Diary of a Modern Pilgrim." This column ran in many newspapers, though it was best-known for being in the Austin-American Statesman.
  - Clippings (1 of 3), circa 1960s (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Clippings (2 of 3), circa 1960s (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Clippings (3 of 3), circa 1960s (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Clippings (1 of 3), circa 1960 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Clippings (2 of 3), circa 1960 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Clippings (3 of 3), circa 1960 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Clippings (1 of 8), 1963-1971 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Clippings (2 of 8), 1963-1971 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Clippings (3 of 8), 1963-1971 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Clippings (4 of 8), 1963-1971 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Clippings (5 of 8), 1963-1971 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Clippings (6 of 8), 1963-1971 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Clippings (7 of 8), 1963-1971 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Clippings (8 of 8), 1963-1971 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Clippings, circa 1973-1976 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Clippings (1 of 2), circa 1969-1976 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Clippings (2 of 2), circa 1969-1976 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Clippings (1 of 2), 1975 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Clippings (2 of 2), 1975 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Clippings (1 of 8), 1972-1976 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Clippings (2 of 8), 1972-1976 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Clippings (3 of 8), 1972-1976 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Clippings (4 of 8), 1972-1976 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Clippings (5 of 8), 1972-1976 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Clippings (6 of 8), 1972-1976 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Clippings (7 of 8), 1972-1976 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Clippings (8 of 8), 1972-1976 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Clippings (1 of 10), 1977-1979 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Clippings (2 of 10), 1977-1979 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Clippings (3 of 10), 1977-1979 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Clippings (4 of 10), 1977-1979 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Clippings (5 of 10), 1977-1979 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Clippings (6 of 10), 1977-1979 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Clippings (7 of 10), 1977-1979 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Clippings (8 of 10), 1977-1979 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Clippings (9 of 10), 1977-1979 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Clippings (10 of 10), 1977-1979 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Clippings (1 of 17), 1966-1988 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Clippings (2 of 17), 1966-1988 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Clippings (3 of 17), 1966-1988 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Clippings (4 of 17), 1966-1988 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Clippings (5 of 17), 1966-1988 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Clippings (6 of 17), 1966-1988 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Clippings (7 of 17), 1966-1988 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Clippings (8 of 17), 1966-1988 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Clippings (9 of 17), 1966-1988 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Clippings (10 of 17), 1966-1988 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Clippings (11 of 17), 1966-1988 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Clippings (12 of 17), 1966-1988 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Clippings (13 of 17), 1966-1988 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Clippings (14 of 17), 1966-1988 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Clippings (15 of 17), 1966-1988 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Clippings (16 of 17), 1966-1988 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Clippings (17 of 17), 1966-1988 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Clippings (1 of 8), 1980-1982 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Clippings (2 of 8), 1980-1982 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Clippings (3 of 8), 1980-1982 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Clippings (4 of 8), 1980-1982 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Clippings (5 of 8), 1980-1982 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Clippings (6 of 8), 1980-1982 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Clippings (7 of 8), 1980-1982 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Clippings (8 of 8), 1980-1982 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Clippings (1 of 2), 1969-1996 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Clippings (2 of 2), 1969-1996 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Clippings (1 of 7), 1995-1999 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Clippings (2 of 7), 1995-1999 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Clippings (3 of 7), 1995-1999 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Clippings (4 of 7), 1995-1999 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Clippings (5 of 7), 1995-1999 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Clippings (6 of 7), 1995-1999 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Clippings (7 of 7), 1995-1999 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Clippings (1 of 6), 1998-2002 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Clippings (2 of 6), 1998-2002 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Clippings (3 of 6), 1998-2002 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Clippings (4 of 6), 1998-2002 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Clippings (5 of 6), 1998-2002 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Clippings (6 of 6), 1998-2002 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Clippings, 2002 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Clippings (1 of 5), 1965-1990 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Clippings (2 of 5), 1965-1990 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Clippings (3 of 5), 1965-1990 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Clippings (4 of 5), 1965-1990 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Clippings (5 of 5), 1965-1990 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Book Manuscript, Diary of a Modern Pilgrim (1 of 4), undated (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Book Manuscript, Diary of a Modern Pilgrim (2 of 4), undated (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Book Manuscript, Diary of a Modern Pilgrim (3 of 4), undated (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Book Manuscript, Diary of a Modern Pilgrim (4 of 4), undated (Box 18, Folder 15)
- Personal Materials, 1949-2000, undated; 3
  This series contains materials from Ware's personal life, including a high school paper he wrote, letters, and documentation of his retirement from his long service as a pastor.
  - Correspondence (1 of 4), 1964 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence (2 of 4), 1964 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence (3 of 4), 1964 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence (4 of 4), 1964 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence (1 of 3), 1971-1973 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence (2 of 3), 1971-1973 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence (3 of 3), 1971-1973 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence (1 of 4), 1971-1975 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence (2 of 4), 1971-1975 (Box 19, Folder 9)